As you probably know, learning a foreign language is sometimes challenging. But it can also be fun.
你很可能知道，学习一门外语有时颇具挑战性，但这个过程也可以充满乐趣。
We spend hundreds of hours at school trying to get our tongues round different vocabulary and grammar in order to earn a qualification.
我们在学校里花费数百小时，努力掌握各种词汇和语法，只为考取相应的证书。
But learning to speak a second language is more than just passing an exam – it opens doors to new opportunities, helps you to communicate with others and makes travelling overseas more fulfilling.
但学会一门第二语言，意义远不止通过一场考试——它能为你打开新的机遇之门，帮助你与他人沟通，还能让海外旅行变得更有收获。
It might come as a surprise that, according to research by the BBC, the number of teenagers learning foreign languages in UK secondary schools has dropped by 45% since the turn of the millennium.
英国广播公司的一项研究显示，自千禧年以来，英国中学里学习外语的青少年人数下降了45%，这个数据或许会让你感到惊讶。
German and French have fallen the most.
其中德语和法语的学习人数降幅最大。
While these languages from two of the UK's closest trading partners have declined at GCSE level, there has been a noticeable surge in some others, such as Spanish and Mandarin.
尽管这两门来自英国最亲密贸易伙伴的语言，在英国普通中等教育证书考试阶段的学习人数有所减少，但其他一些语言的学习人数却出现了显著增长，例如西班牙语和汉语普通话。
Another survey of secondary schools suggests a third of students have dropped at least one language from their GCSE exam options.
另一项针对中学的调查显示，三分之一的学生从自己的英国普通中等教育证书考试选考科目中，至少放弃了一门语言类学科。
There are many reasons for this, including a perception by some students that languages are difficult.
背后的原因有很多，包括部分学生认为语言学习难度较高。
Getting to grips with the lingo of another country can certainly be a challenge and some pupils think 'Why bother?' when English is spoken by hundreds of millions of people worldwide.
熟练掌握另一国的语言体系确实是一项挑战，而且考虑到全球有上亿人说英语，一些学生就会觉得“何必费这个劲呢？”
Others have questioned the need for a second language when translation technology is advancing.
还有一些人质疑随着翻译技术的不断进步，是否还有必要学习第二语言。
Matthew Fell, chief UK policy director for business group the CBI, has told the BBC that "The decline in language learning in schools must be reversed, or else the UK will be less competitive globally and young people less prepared for the modern world."
英国工业联合会的英国首席政策总监马修·菲尔向英国广播公司表示：“学校外语学习人数下降的趋势必须得到扭转，否则英国的全球竞争力将会下降，年轻人也无法更好地应对现代社会的挑战。”
But even for those who are keen to study another language, the opportunity is being reduced.
但即便是对于那些热衷于学习外语的学生来说，学习机会也在不断减少。
In Scotland, for example, foreign language subjects are being squeezed out of many secondary school timetables with some head teachers blaming pressure on the curriculum.
例如在苏格兰，很多中学的课程表中已经不再安排外语科目，一些校长将此归咎于课程安排的压力。
However, some native English speakers have told the BBC about the benefits of speaking another tongue.
不过，一些以英语为母语的人向英国广播公司讲述了掌握另一门语言的诸多好处。
Cassandra Scott, from Edinburgh, studied three languages in her final year at school. She is now a freelance translator in Edinburgh, and says "Learning languages at school really set the course for my career."
来自爱丁堡的卡桑德拉·斯科特在中学最后一年学习了三门语言，如今她是一名在爱丁堡工作的自由译者，她表示：“中学阶段的语言学习，确实为我的职业生涯奠定了基础。”